Guide to the Alan Behr Photographs 1991, 2000-2021 PR 434
New-York Historical Society
Alan Behr photographs
1991, 2000-2021
New-York Historical Society
Behr, Alan
PR 434
3.5 Linear feet in 2 flat boxes
The collection holds 142 black-and-white photographs by Alan Behr. 80 of the photos are from Behr's series "Naked at the Ball," which are scenes from the party and benefit circuit on Manhattan's Upper East Side. 61 photos are from his series "New York During the Covid-19 Lockdown," which captures New Yorkers going about their lives, masked or unmasked, during the coronavirus pandemic.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in three series:
Series I. "Naked at the Ball"
Series II. "New York During the Covid-19 Lockdown"
Series III. Other Subjects
Biographical / Historical
Alan Behr is a writer, photographer and lawyer. A partner in the firm of Phillips Nizer LLP, Behr's practice concentrates on international intellectual property, fashion, and entertainment law. As part of the firm's active art practice, Behr represents artists, art galleries, art investors and collectors, and photographers and photography rights holders, of which he is one. Behr's photography centers on travel and on people in the context of their work, leisure, street life, and other social settings. Many of his images and written works have been published. Behr is a dual United States-German citizen, and lives in New York City.
(The above note is based on Alan Behr's biographical sketches on Phillips Nizer's website and on the site Behr maintains regarding his photography and writing interests.)
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers by appointment only. Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact printroom@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the photographer, Alan Behr, in 2020 and 2021.
Scope and Contents
The collection holds 142 black and white photographs taken by Alan Behr. 80 of the photos are from Behr's series "Naked at the Ball," which are scenes from the party and benefit circuit on Manhattan's Upper East Side. 61 photos are from Behr's series "New York During the Covid-19 Lockdown," which captures New Yorkers going about their lives, masked or unmasked, during the coronavirus pandemic. One photo is of a group of women reacting to the destruction of the World Trade Center towers on September 11, 2001.
All the photographs are signed by Alan Behr. Almost all are captioned by the photographer on the reverse, with title, location, and year. These captions were used in the finding aid's list of photographs. The photographer included an inventory of donated titles with his gift; in a few cases the inventory information differed from the caption. In those cases, the caption was used in the finding aid list, but the alternative information from the inventory was noted. In a few cases, the inventory provided somewhat more, but not factually different, information than the caption did; for those, the finding aid list drew on both sources.
Black-and-white photographs.; Balls (Parties) -- New York (State) -- New York.; COVID-19 Pandemic, 2020- -- New York (State) -- New York.; Street life -- New York (State) -- New York.; Upper class -- New York (State) -- New York.; Upper East Side (New York, N.Y.)
- Series I. "Naked at the Ball", 1991, 2000-2020
  Scope and Contents
  The series holds 80 black-and-white photographs from Alan Behr's series "Naked at the Ball." On his website, Behr describes the series as follows: "The Naked at the Ball series is an inside look at the party and benefit circuit on Manhattan's Upper East Side. Taken by Alan Behr while a guest at social events, they capture what is, by the standards of the milieu, images of ordinary life made in moments of leisure."
  A selection of photographs from Behr's series, representative of the larger number held at N-YHS, can be found on his website at: https://alanbehr.com/naked-at-the-ball/
  Arrangement
  The series is organized/foldered by size of photograph, then chronologically within each size. Folder 1 holds 17 x 22 inch photographs; folder 2 holds 16 x 20 inch; folder 3 holds 13 x 19 inch; folder 4 holds 13 x 17 inch; and folder 5 holds 11 x 14 inch.
  - 17 x 22 inch photographs (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Tiffany & Co., 2000 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dancing, Waldorf Astoria, 2003 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    The photo's caption is dated 2003; the donor's inventory is dated 2013.
  - Salvatore Ferragamo Opening Night, 2003 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Birthday Party, 2006 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dancers, Disco Hour, 2006 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Museum Party, 2008 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dancers, Opera Ball, Waldorf Astoria, 2012 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Media, 2013 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dancers, Museum of the City of New York, 2016 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Antique Cartography, The Winter Show, 2019 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - 16 x 20 inch photographs (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - Party, Saks Fifth Avenue, 2000 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - Blackjack, Sotheby's, 2006 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - Waiters, Christian Dior, 2007 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - Naked at the Ball, 2008 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - 13 x 19 inch photographs (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Two Women, Patio, 2000 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woman in Knit Dress, 2006 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woman in Knotted Hat, Waldorf Astoria, 2017 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woman in Goat Mask, Cipriani, 2017 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Debutante, Austrian Consulate General, 2019 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Leaving the Dance Floor, University Club, 2019 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Man with Two Champagne Glasses, 2019 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Men with Mobile Phone, University Club, 2019 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Woman with Diamond Drop Earrings, University Club, 2019 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - 13 x 17 inch photographs (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Two Women, Patio, 2000 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Museum of Natural History, 2001 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Rubbing Shoulders, 2004 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Million Dollar Necklace, Cartier, 2005 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Party, Judith Ripka, 2006 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Woman in a Knit Dress, 2006 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Three Women in Black, 2007 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    The photograph caption is dated 2007; the donor's inventory is dated 2002.
  - Woman with a Fan, 2007 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Woman with Two Fans, 2008 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - After-Dinner Drinks, The Plaza, 2009 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    The photograph caption places this at the Plaza; the donor's inventory places it at the Pierre.
  - Alan Behr, Grand Ballroom, The Plaza, 2009 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Operagoers, Opening Night, 2009 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Benefactors' Preview, 2010 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Before the Ball, 2011 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Candelabra Bearer, The Pierre, 2011 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Greeting, Payne Whitney House, 2011 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    The photograph caption is dated 2011; the donor's inventory dates it as 2017.
  - Joyful Dancing, 2011 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Discussion, Waldorf Astoria, 2012 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - White Tie Kiss, 2012 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Red Carpet, Opening Night, 2015 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Winter Show, The Armory, 2015 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Woman in a Headband, The Pierre, 2015 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Model, Four Seasons Restaurant, 2016 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Please Be Seated, The Pierre, 2016 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Preparations, The Pierre, 2016 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Seated Woman, The Pierre, 2016 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Antique Cartography, The Winter Show, 2019 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dance Floor, The Pierre, 2020 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Selfie, The Pierre, 2020 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Two Women Dancing, The Pierre, 2020 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - West Point Cadet with a Recent Debutante, The Pierre, 2020 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - 11 x 14 inch photographs (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Opening Night, Sonnabend Gallery, 1991 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Young Guests, Waldorf Astoria, 2000 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - New Year's Eve, Lenox Room, 2001 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - New Year's Eve, 59th Street Station, 2002 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    The photograph caption is dated 2002; the donor's inventory dates it as 2003.
  - Party, The Frick Collection, 2005 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Woman in Fur, Cocktails, 2005 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bartenders, 2006 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dancing, Christmas Party, 2006 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Christmas Party, 2006 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - In the Tent, 2006 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Three Women, Cocktails, 2007 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Woman in Black Evening Gown, 2007 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dancers, Museum Party, Museum of the City of New York, 2007 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dancers, Disco Hour, 2008 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    The photograph caption is dated 2008; the donor's inventory is dated 2006.
  - After Party, 2008 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Book Party, 2009 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - After-Dinner Drinks, The Plaza, 2009 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Swing Dancing, Grand Ballroom, 2009 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Committee, The Plaza, 2009 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dinner, The Plaza, 2009 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Woman with Pearl Earrings, 2009 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Twins, Preview Night, 2010 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Two Women, Tiffany & Co., 2010 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cheek Kiss, Tiffany & Co., 2010 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bill Cunningham, Winter Ball, 2015 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Waltz, Waldorf Astoria, 2017 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
- Series III. "New York During the Covid-19 Lockdown", 2020-2021
  The series holds 61 black-and-white photographs taken by Alan Behr during the 2020-2021 Covid-19 coronavirus pandemic. The images recall the health care workers, delivery persons, street buskers, subway riders, wait staff, museum guards, doormen, and others continuing to work in the city and on its streets, in their service industry jobs, in the midst of the pandemic. Children playing, joggers, people walking dogs, protesters, and others are captured in scenes that are often typical of New York street life, with the exception that wearing--or not wearing--a mask as a safeguard against contagion is a prominent detail within the larger image.
  The series is organized by the two sizes of photographs: 13 x 19 inch in folder 1, and 11 x 17 inch in folders 2 and 3, then alphabetical by title.
  - 13 x 19 inch photographs (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Cafe, Third Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Caterer, Lexington Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, "Cultivate Kindness," Columbus Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Dentist, East 48th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
    The photograph caption indicates 48th Street; the donor inventory indicates 49th Street.
  - Pandemic, Driver, Madison Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Empty Food Carts, Fifth Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Harmonica Player, Second Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Healthcare Worker Photographing a Horse, Lenox Hill Hospital, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Kick the Can, East 92nd Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Kneeling Protesters, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Man Passing Bottles, Prince Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
    The photograph caption places this at Prince Street; the donor's inventory places it at Pine Street.
  - Pandemic, Man Running, East 86th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Man with Takeout Food, East 81st Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
    The location was taken from the donor's inventory; the photograph caption does not include it.
  - Pandemic, Newsstand, East 86th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Nick [Doorman], East 74th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Painter, East 86th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Passing Ambulance, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Patient Arriving at Mount Sinai Hospital, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Pedestrian, East 59th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Police Car Speeding Through the Rain, Lexington Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Real Estate Listings, Madison Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Schoolboy, Central Park, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Self-Portrait, Lexington Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Self-Portrait with Leo [Barber], 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Service Restored, East 95th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Waiting for the Traffic Signal, Madison Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Woman Covering Her Face, Madison Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Woman Passing Posters, Lafayette Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Woman Reading, Central Park, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pandemic, Woman Walking a Dog, Lexington Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - 11 x 17 inch photographs (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Ambulance Team, Lenox Hill Hospital, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Blowing the Shofar, East 96th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Boy on a Scooter, Third Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Chalk Drawing, Third Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Cocktails, East 64th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Concierge, East 95th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Jogger, Central Park Reservoir, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Man with a Snack, Lexington Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Man with Cocktail, East 64th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Man with Coffee, Lexington Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Man with Birds, East 86th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Man Walking a Dog, East 85th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Open Late, Third Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Painter, East 95th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Protest at Michael Bloomberg's House, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Security Guard with a Dog, Fifth Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Seven O'clock Cheer, East 95th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Sidewalk Dining on Second Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Singer, East 86th Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Woman on the Q Train, Southbound, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Woman Passing Posters on Lafayette Street, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Woman Skipping Rope, Third Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Woman Walking Two Dogs, Second Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pandemic, Woman with an Improvised Face Mask, Madison Avenue, 2020 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - 11 x 17 inch photographs (2021) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pandemic, Children in Strollers, Second Avenue, 2021 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pandemic, Four Boys, the 6 Train, 2021 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pandemic, Full Reopening Day, Madison Avenue, 2021 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pandemic, Full Reopening Day, Park Avenue, 2021 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pandemic, Guard with Portraits, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 2021 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pandemic, Peggy McCarthy Vaccinates Me, 2021 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pandemic, Senator Schumer in Union Square, 2021 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
- Series III. Other Subjects, 2001
  The series holds one photograph from Alan Behr's "People" series. This image is an 11 x 14 inch silver gelatin print of a group of people looking with concern and fright at something behind the camera; taken on Fifth Avenue and dated the morning of 9/11/2001 the object of attention is no doubt the World Trade Center after the terrorist attack.
  - 9.11.01, Fifth Avenue, 10.15 a.m., 2001 September 11 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)